Rodney Ovbiye

☑ rodneyovbiye@gmail.com 📞 +234 8113514748 in Rodney Ovbiye 🕡 Rodney-glitch

▶ https://rodney-portfolio.netlify.app/ M https://medium.com/@rodneyovbiye

PROFILE

Certified Software Test Engineer with experience in API Testing, Functional Testing, Writing Test Scripts, and Regression Testing with the use of Automation. Exposed to Software Development Life Cycle, Software Testing Life Cycle and Bug Life Cycle. Driven to ensure high-quality delivery of tasks through a personal philosophy of continuous learning and being teachable as well as the ability to communicate clearly and concisely.

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Java, JavaScript, Python

CI/CD and Version Control

Git, GitHub, CircleCI, Jenkins

Soft Skills

Teamwork, Analytical, Communication, Strategic Planning & Executions, Leadership

Tools

Cypress, Selenium, Postman, Apache JMeter, Katalon, React, Microsoft excel, Rest Assured, JIRA, Trello

Testing Types

Automated Testing, Manual Testing, API Testing, Performance Testing, Functional Testing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Jun 2021 - present Lagos, Nigeria

Seamfix

Test Automation Engineer

- Automated 4 high priority projects with **Selenium** and **Cypress** reduced the regression time by 80% through converting 90% of manual testcases to automated scripts.
- Created framework for **cypress**, which was used across the company to automate new projects.
- Wrote **Test Scripts** from Acceptance Criteria to test new implementations and
- Carried out tests to identify, report and repair issues such as bugs and defects.
- Managed and wrote automation scripts for automating API services in **Rest** Assured.
- Participated in product and design sessions with developers, UI designers and product managers to start early testing and improve quality at early stages.

Jan 2021 – Jun 2021 Lagos, Nigeria

Quales Consulting

Software Tester

- Created Test Scripts to test **APIs** in Postman.
- Tutored colleagues on the ISTQB syllabus before taking the exam.
- Wrote **test cases** that accelerated the productivity in the TDLC.
- Reported bugs on boards using Trello.
- Automated tests to reduce time taken to perform regression testing using Selenium (Java).
- Analyzed raw data sheets using tools such as Vlookup, match, index, etc.

Jan 2020 – Jun 2020 Edo, Nigeria

Nigerian Petroleum Development Company

IT Support

- Inspected new systems to test the necessary drivers and software and approve that they are up to standard before distributing to users.
- Directly responsible for managing the Managing Director's boardroom, overseeing all IT services needed.

PROJECTS

World Population Count

Java, Selenium, TestNG, Maven, PostgreSQL

- Developed an automated script with **Selenium** (**Java**) that gets the counting total population of the world from a website every second for a specific time.
- Utilized the **TestNG** annotations to managed the test methods.
- Integrated **PostgreSQL** which was used to store the data with **Maven** to manage all dependencies.

End to End Automation on Online Shopping Mall

JavaScript, Cypress, Cypress Dashboard

- Implemented the use of Page Object Model (POM) to store HTML elements.
- Created commands to reduce repetitive codes and follow the principles of DRY (Don't Repeat Your Code).
- Worked with the Cypress Dashboard to give a more presentable report to client and also capture the video of test runs.

EDUCATION

Sep 2017 – Jun 2021

B.Sc Computer Science

Nigeria

Babcock University

CERTIFICATES

ISTQB® - **International Software Testing Qualifications Board** (Certified Tester Foundation Level (CTFL))